Joe Barker

Mobile Developer

Contact

Phone (+44) 07722181882

E-mail

joe.joeb29@gmail.com

Portfolio

https://joegec.github.io/portfolio/

Github

github.com/JoeGeC/

Linked-In

linkedin.com/in/joe-barker-

Over 4 years of hands-on experience in native Android, Flutter and Xamarin development and 2 of my own apps previously released on the Google Play Store. I have a Passion for Clean Code and Clean Architecture, including SOLID principles and Test-Driven Development. Demonstrated proficiency with Android Development in Kotlin and Java at Other Media and Mkodo, Flutter Development at KnockKnock, and Xamarin development in C# and test automation in Javascript at my time at Mkodo.

Work Experience

Oct. 2024 -Current

Senior Flutter Developer - *KnockKnock (Contract)*

- Leading the development of new features, ensuring seamless integration with the existing app.
- Wrote and maintained unit tests to improve code reliability and maintainability.
- Provided training and mentorship on Clean Architecture,
 Flutter best practices, and mobile development principles to enhance the team's technical skills.

Nov. 2023 -Oct. 2024

Career Break

 A year off to expand my experience and knowledge while travelling. I spent a lot of time working on side projects and training for myself.

Apr. 2022 -Nov. 2023

Android Developer - Other Media

- Worked on a challenging white-label native app, making features and UX/UI flexible and maintainable for future clients.
- Working with and refactoring legacy code in Java and Kotlin.
- Bringing the development team up to speed on Test-Driven Development.

Sep. 2021 -Apr. 2022

Android Developer - *Mkodo*

- Developing native Android applications using MVVM, Jetpack Compose, Retrofit and Room.
- Developing cross-platform applications in Xamarin, using MVP and clean architecture/domain driven design.
- Utilising test-driven development to write clean code.
- Working in an agile environment.

Aug. 2019 -Aug. 2020

Intern Mobile Developer - Mkodo

- Developed Xamarin and native Android apps within teams.
- Learned the benefits of writing clean code and architecture using test-driven development and design patterns.
- Gained knowledge from software engineers such as Robert C.
 Martin and Kent Beck.
- Gained experience of test automation and QA and the perspective it brings as a developer.
- Worked in an agile environment within several teams.
- Presented work to clients and attended industry events.
- Hosted talks to the 30-person development team about technologies I'd been working with.

Aug. 2016 -Jan. 2017

Apprentice Mobile Developer - Thumbmunkeys

• Trained in Xamarin and C#, Git proficiency and working in a team to meet deadlines and deliver the product to the client.

Joe Barker

Mobile Developer

Skills

Kotlin

Java

Dart

C#

C++

Javascript

Python

XAML

XML

JSON

SQL

Android Development

JUnit

Jetpack Compose

Retrofit

Room

Flow

LiveData

Hilt/Dagger

Flutter Development

BloC

Dio

L10n

GoRouter

SQLite

Xamarin

Test-Driven Development Clean Architecture SOLID Principles Gherkin/Cucumber MVVM & MVP

Tutoring

Jan. 2021 -Current

Programming Tutor - *Self-Employed*

Tutoring students and young professionals on programming to the industry standard, TDD, and giving help and guidance on school and university projects.

Sept. 2018 -May 2019 Pass Leader - Teesside University

Leading peer assisted study sessions each week to help first year students study the programming modules I had done previously.

Portfolio

MovieDB Written Using Jetpack Compose

- Written using jetpack compose for UI, ViewModels and StateFlow.
- Uses common Android libraries such as Retrofit, Room, Hilt.
- Clean architecture modularised by feature.
- Full suite of unit tests using JUnit and Mockito.
- Github (Readme!) https://github.com/JoeGeC/MovieApp-Android

Pokedex App Written in Flutter

- A Flutter app pulling from a REST API using Dio, SQLite, Bloc, L10n.
- Comprehensive unit testing, integration testing and clean architecture.
- Smooth animations and caching.
- Clean architecture modularised by layer.
- Github (Readme!) https://github.com/JoeGeC/PokemonDbFlutter

Quotes - A Native Android App Written in Kotlin and Using Firebase

- Classic Android app about tracking the silly quotes that friends say.
- Using test-driven development and clean architecture to develop a codebase that is expandable and robust.
- Using Firebase for the backend and authentication.
- Previously released and maintained for 3 years on the Google Play Store.

Education

Sept. 2017 -June 2021

Bsc: Computer Games Programming

Teesside University

• First-class honours degree

Interests

Logic Puzzles/Games

I have always loved the logic surrounding puzzles and games such as Chess and Rubik's Cubes and have never been one to shy away from a problem, especially a technological one.

Languages

Learning to speak Spanish gave me a renewed passion and drive to learn languages, it keeps my mind active and opens up a lot of connections when travelling. I'm now learning Japanese, a big challenge, but very rewarding.

Travel

Travelling to different cultures on a tight budget has allowed me to make friends from every continent, made me much more open-minded and introduced me to a passion of cooking and food.